Guide to the Gleb Struve Papers, 1889-1979
Department of Special Collections
Struve, Gleb. Papers,
1889-1979
M0874
Struve, Gleb
.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Photocopies and reprints of literary works, and some serial publications relating to Slavic literature. Includes two children's books belonging to Marina Struve.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Gleb Struve, 1996.
Biography
Russian-American literary historian and critic; professor of Slavic languages and literatures, University of California, Berkeley, 1947-1967.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Photocopies and reprints of literary works, and some serial publications relating to Slavic literature. Includes two children's books belonging to Marina Struve.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Altman, Moisei Semenovich.; Bulgakov, Mikhail.; Chukovskii, Kornei.; Chukhontsev, Oleg.; Grigorian, Leonid.; Gumilev, Nikolai.; Khodasevich, Vladimir.; Krylov, A.; Moravskaia, Mariia.; Miroglio, Abel.; Russian literature--20th century.; Russia--Civilization.; Soviet Union.; Ocharovannyi strannik.; Vstrecha.; Znameniia nashikh dnei.; Bashnia strazhi.; Khristianin.; Voenno-istoricheskii vestnik.; Pervopokhodnik.; Novaia Rossiia.; Arsenal ateizma.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Manuscripts and Articles
  - Altman, Moisei Semenovich. [Poems of Moisei Semenovich Al'tman] [1 of 2], photocopy (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Altman, Moisei Semenovich. [Poems of Moisei Semenovich Al'tman] [2 of 2], photocopy (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miroglio, Abel. L'emigration russe, sex aspirations ...: article, photocopy (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gumilev, Nikolai. Ten ot palmy. -- [Petrograd], 1922, printout of microfilm, lacking t.p. Identified by typed pages 20-21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Khodasevich, Vladimir. Voina v russkoi lirike. -- (Universalnaia biblioteka; no. 960). -- Moskva: K-vo "Polza", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Omfalaticheskii olimp: zabytye poety. -- Odessa: Omfalos, 1918, original and photocopy (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Collection of preprints of articles belonging to UCLA papers in syntax series? On Russian and other Slavic literature (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Selections from No. 1-10 of the publication Ocharovannyi strannik. -- Petrograd,1913 - 1916, photocopies, lacking tps (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Moravskai, Mariia. Apel'sinnye korki. -- St. Petersburg, 1914, photocopy, lacking tp (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Small poetry collections1922 - 1976, photocopies (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Sviashchennaia lira (Warszawa: Zarubezhe, 1938) -- Chasy. Chas 1 (Petersburg, 1922) -- Ushniki (Petersburg, 1922) -- Vygodskii, D. Zemle: stikhi ([S.l.: s.n.], 1922) -- Grigor'ian, Leonid. Pero: stikhi (Rostov-na-Donu: Rostovskoe knizhnoe izd-vo, 1968) -- Chukhontsev, Oleg. Iz trekh tetradei: stikhi (Moskva: Sov. pisatel, 1976)
  - Bulgakov, Mikhail. Master i Margarita: neizdannye otryvki i epizody. -- Bern: Scherz Verlag, 1967, galley (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes a list of translations of certain lines.
  - Two childrens books belonging to Marina Struven.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Krylov, A. Volk I zhuravl (Moskva: J. Knebel, n.d.) -- Chukovskii, Kornei. Moidodyr (lacks covers)
- Series 2. Serial Publications
  - Vstrecha, Sb.2 / edited by Sergei Makovskii. -- Paris1945 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Znameniia nashikh dnei. -- San Francisco, Calif., 3 issues (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bashnia strazhi. -- Russian ed. of Watch tower. -- Brooklyn, N.Y., 1963 June (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Khristianin: a Russian Baptist magazine, no. 34. -- [Nashville]: Home Mission Board Direct Missions, Southern Baptist Convention, [ca. 197-] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Voenno-istoricheskii vestnik. -- Paris: Izd. Ob-va revnitelei russkoi voennoi stariny, 4 issues (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pervopokhodnik, no. 21. -- Los Angeles, Calif.: Izd. Ob'edineniia pervopokhodnikov (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Novaia Rossia. -- Petrograd-Moskva: Frenkel,1922, 1 issue, no designation (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series 3. Other Books
  - Arsenal ateizma. -- Paris: Le Choix, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Supplement to No. 12/13 of Le Choix
  - Glavnye resultaty urzhaia 1889 goda. -- (Vremennik Tsentalnago statisticheskago komite Ministerstva vnutrennikh diel, no. 15 (1890)) -- St. Petersburg: Tsentralnyi statisticheskii kom-t Min-va vnutrennikh diel,1899 (Box 2, Folder 4)